export const DATA = [
  {
    id: 1,
    consonants: [
      {
        id: "1",
        front: "ㄴ",
        back: "N",
      },
      {
        id: "2",
        front: "ㄱ",
        back: "G",
      },
      {
        id: "3",
        front: "ㅁ",
        back: "M",
      },
      {
        id: "4",
        front: "ㅇ",
        back: "N/ng",
      },
      {
        id: "5",
        front: "ㅅ",
        back: "S",
      },
      {
        id: "6",
        front: "ㅈ",
        back: "J",
      },
      {
        id: "7",
        front: "ㅊ",
        back: "ch",
      },
      {
        id: "8",
        front: "ㄹ",
        back: "R/L",
      },
      {
        id: "9",
        front: "ㅍ",
        back: "P",
      },
      {
        id: "10",
        front: "ㅂ",
        back: "B",
      },
      {
        id: "11",
        front: "ㅌ",
        back: "T",
      },
      {
        id: "12",
        front: "ㅎ",
        back: "H",
      },
      {
        id: "13",
        front: "ㅋ",
        back: "K",
      },
      {
        id: "14",
        front: "ㄲ",
        back: "KK",
      },
      {
        id: "15",
        front: "ㅃ",
        back: "PP",
      },
      {
        id: "16",
        front: "ㅆ",
        back: "SS",
      },
      {
        id: "17",
        front: "ㄷ",
        back: "D",
      },
      {
        id: "18",
        front: "ㄸ",
        back: "tt",
      },
      {
        id: "19",
        front: "ㅉ",
        back: "jj",
      },
    ],
    vowels: [
      {
        id: "1",
        front: "ㅓ",
        back: "eo",
      },
      {
        id: "2",
        front: "ㅏ",
        back: "A",
      },
      {
        id: "3",
        front: "ㅣ",
        back: "E",
      },
      {
        id: "4",
        front: "ㅡ",
        back: "eu/oh",
      },
      {
        id: "5",
        front: "ㅗ",
        back: "O",
      },
      {
        id: "6",
        front: "ㅜ",
        back: "uh",
      },
      {
        id: "7",
        front: "ㅠ",
        back: "yu",
      },
      {
        id: "8",
        front: "ㅛ",
        back: "yo",
      },
      {
        id: "9",
        front: "ㅖ",
        back: "ye",
      },
      {
        id: "10",
        front: "ㅑ",
        back: "ya",
      },
      {
        id: "11",
        front: "ㅕ",
        back: "yeo",
      },
      {
        id: "12",
        front: "ㅔ",
        back: "ey",
      },
      {
        id: "13",
        front: "ㅐ",
        back: "ae",
      },
    ],
  },
];
